<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>io.github.HakanSeven12.H7CAD</id>

  <name>H7CAD</name>
  <summary>A CAD application for 2D/3D drawing and design</summary>

  <metadata_license>MIT</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-only</project_license>

  <description>
    <p>
      H7CAD is a computer-aided design (CAD) application built with Rust.
      It supports 2D drafting and 3D modeling with GPU-accelerated rendering,
      and can open and work with DXF files.
    </p>
    <ul>
      <li>2D and 3D drawing tools</li>
      <li>DXF file import/export</li>
      <li>GPU-accelerated rendering via WebGPU</li>
      <li>Snap and annotation tools</li>
    </ul>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.HakanSeven12.H7CAD.desktop</launchable>

  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/HakanSeven12/H7CAD</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/HakanSeven12/H7CAD/issues</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/HakanSeven12/H7CAD</url>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>Main application window</caption>
      <image>https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/25bc2bb2-c35c-477d-a3e9-45c86690b5c9</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <releases>
    <release version="0.2.8" date="2026-05-15">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed major precision loss on UTM-authored drawings: world_offset now derives from the median of MSPACE entity centroids instead of the DXF $EXTMIN/$EXTMAX midpoint, so a single stray entity can no longer drag the offset hundreds of kilometres away from the real geometry (about 120× better precision on the affected files).</li>
          <li>Fixed Zoom Extents collapsing the drawing to sub-pixel size on files with orphan or block-defn entities leaking into model space.</li>
          <li>Fixed phantom selectable segments from BLOCK / ENDBLK sentinels showing up far from the visible drawing.</li>
          <li>Fixed two text rendering bugs: greek (sub-pixel) rectangle now fills at the text's own color, and the rectangle honours word-wrapped sub-line count.</li>
          <li>Performance: multi-resolution mesh LOD for 3D solids — the render pipeline now picks one of three pre-built tessellation densities per frame based on projected pixel size.</li>
          <li>Performance: hatch LOD substitutes solid fill when pattern spacing falls below ~2 px, and skips draw calls entirely when the whole hatch projects to sub-pixel size.</li>
          <li>Performance: zoom-adaptive curve tolerance for top-level wires — distant arcs no longer emit hundreds of segments that all collapse onto one pixel.</li>
          <li>Performance: text LOD ladder (baseline-line / greek / full) now also applies to MultiLeader text content.</li>
          <li>Performance: paper-space viewport scissor extended to hatch / image / wipeout passes (in addition to the existing wire scissor).</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.2.2" date="2026-05-03">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed creating a new drawing so existing open files remain in their tabs.</li>
          <li>Fixed arc creation to preserve clicked positions and keep internal arc angles in radians.</li>
          <li>Improved OCS/WCS handling, snap points, hatch boundary rendering, and thickness extrusion support.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.0" date="2026-03-22">
      <description>
        <p>Initial release of H7CAD.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />

  <developer id="io.github.hakanseven12">
    <name>Hakan Seven</name>
  </developer>
</component>
